Guide to the Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Professional Activities, 1941-1996
  - Subseries III.1: General, 1941-1996
    - Manual of Research Techniques in Medieval and Renaissance Hinstory
      - Notes and Drafts, 1982-1995 (Box 90)
      - Drafts and Correspondence, 1994 (Box 90)
      - Correspondence with Cynthia Pyle, 1993-1994 (Box 90)
      - Manuscript Drafts, 1995-1996 (Box 91)
    - Manuscripts Catalog
      - Bibliographies, 1957 (Box 91)
      - Microfilm Catalogue of POK, undated (Box 91)
      - Microfilm Program, 1946-1961, (3 Folders) (Box 91)
    - Mauro, Thomas (Box 91)
    - Mediaeval Academy of America, 1959-1983, (5 Folders) (Box 91)
    - Medieval and Renaissance Encyclopedia--Proposals, 1945-1946 (Box 91)
    - Microfilm Conference--Proposed, 1967-1968 (Box 91)
    - Microfilm Corpus, 1986-1987 (Box 91)
    - Microfilm and Photostat Collection Lists, 1962-1987 (Box 91)
    - Monfasani, John--"Ad Divinum Paulum…" (Box 91)
    - Moyer, Ann-- "Brandolinus: De Musica et Poetica," 1989 (Box 91)
    - Naldi--Grant, Leonard, 1965-1974 (Box 91)
    - National Gallery of Art (Ginerva De'Benci), 1967-1969 (Box 91)
    - Peroso and Cordie--"Folengus, Nicodemus, and Theophilus," 1987-1989 (Box 91)
    - Philology and History Seminar, 1993-1994 (Box 91)
    - Pisa Lectures (Columbia University Press), 1980-1992 (Box 92)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1992 (Box 92)
    - Pomponazzi, 1968-1971 (Box 92)
    - Pyle, Cynthia, 1992 (Box 92)
    - Renaissance Club--New York City, 1945-1947 (Box 92)
    - Renaissance Society of America
      - General, 1953-1979, (8 Folders) (Box 92)
      - Bennett, Josephine--Correspondence, 1954-1960 (Box 92)
      - Committee on International Cooperation, 1953-1958, (3 Folders) (Box 92)
    - Richards, John, 1963-1966 (Box 92)
    - Salz, Jerome (Box 92)
    - Sanford, Eva Matthews, 1952-1954 (Box 92)
    - Schnusenberg, Christine, 1996 (Box 92)
    - The State of Learning in the Humanities of Higher Education, 1980-1985, (5 Folders) (Box 93)
    - Studies in Renaissance Thought and Letters, 1978-1995, (15 Folders) (Box 93)
      (contains correspondence, permissions agreements, distribution lists and manuscripts)
    - Text File, 1941-1977 (Box 94-95)
    - Todd, Robert-- Themistius (Box 93)
    - Weiss, Helen, 1936-1940 (Box 93)
    - Zintzaen, Clemens, 1938 (Box 93)
  - Subseries III.2: Catalogus Translationum et Commentariorum, 1942-1986
    Referred to as CTC, the Catalogus Translationus et Commentariorum is a compilation of Mediaeval and Renaissance Latin translations and commentaries. Subseries 2 is comprised of two sections, correspondence and topical files. Correspondence is arranged by date, with some alphabetized folders, including a portion on the Editorial Board. Multiple people can be found in all three areas. Topical files are alphabetized with an emphasis on Greek and Latin author lists, Libanius, Persius, contributors (under Subject Files), and a draft of Volume I.
    - General Correspondence
      - 1945-1948 (Box 96)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 96)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 96)
      - 1952-1954 (Box 96)
      - 1955-1957 (Box 96)
      - 1957-1959 (Box 96)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 96)
      - 1970 (Box 96)
      - 1971 (Box 96)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 96)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 96)
      - 1973 (Box 96)
      - 1974 (Box 96)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 96)
      - 1975 (Box 96)
      - 1976, (2 Folders) (Box 97)
      - 1977 (Box 97)
      - 1978 (Box 97)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 97)
      - 1979-1986 (Box 97)
      - 1990 (Box 97)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 97)
      - 1994-1996 (Box 97)
      - 1997 (Box 97)
    - Alphabetical Correspondence
      - A through L, 1946-1948 (Box 97)
      - M through Z, 1946-1948 (Box 97)
    - Editorial Board
      - 1942-1946 (Box 97)
      - 1947-1952 (Box 97)
      - 1954-1961 (Box 97)
      - 1962-1966 (Box 98)
      - 1967 (Box 98)
      - Hutton, James, 1942-1957 (Box 98)
      - Hutton, James, 1957-1972 (Box 98)
      - Kibre, Pearl, 1946-1948 (Box 98)
    - Addenda and Corrigenda, 1972-1975 (Box 98)
    - Bibliography, 1946-1948 (Box 98)
    - Bibliography, 1950-1958 (Box 98)
    - Bibliography (Box 99)
      (card file)
    - Cranz, Edward--Correspondence, 1953-1958 (Box 98)
    - Cranz, Edward--Manuscripts, 1954 (Box 98)
    - Floridi, Luciano, 1993-1999 (Box 98)
    - General, 1952-1978 (Box 98)
    - General, 1978 (Box 98)
    - Greek Author Lists
      - 1948 (Box 98)
      - 1950-1952 (Box 98)
      - 1953-1955 (Box 98)
      - 1955-1959 (Box 98)
    - Klustein, Ilana, 1965-1982 (Box 98)
    - Latin Author Lists, 1953 (Box 98)
    - Libanius, 1953-1969 (Box 100)
    - Libanius, 1955-1965 (Box 100)
    - Lockwood, Robert, 1980 (Box 100)
    - Marsh, David,-- Xenophon, 1988-1989 (Box 100)
    - Persius
      - 1972 (Box 100)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 100)
      - 1979 (Box 100)
    - Published Articles, 1948-1956 (Box 100)
    - Sample Entries for Commentaries, 1946-1947 (Box 100)
    - Sample Entries for Translations, 1947-1948 (Box 100)
    - Seneff, Susan, 1981-1982 (Box 100)
    - Subject Files
      - Contributor's Reports
        - 1945-1947 (Box 100)
        - 1948-1951 (Box 100)
        - 1951-1952 (Box 100)
        - 1953-1954 (Box 100)
      - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1946-1948 (Box 100)
      - Project Documents, 1946-1948 (Box 100)
      - Project Documents, 1948-1950 (Box 100)
      - Societies
        - 1944-1946 (Box 100)
        - 1947-1949 (Box 100)
        - 1950-1951 (Box 100)
        - 1952-1968 (Box 100)
    - Supplementary Translations and Addenda to Bibliography, 1950-1951 (Box 101)
    - Vergil, 1975 (Box 101)
    - Volume I
      - Page Proofs, 1959, (2 Folders) (Box 101)
      - Page Proofs with Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 101)
      - Typescript through Page 120, [1950s1960s] (Box 101)
      - Typescript Pages 121 through 410, [1950s-1960s] (Box 101)
      - Typescript Pages 411 through End, [1950s-1960s] (Box 101)
    - Card Files: Bibliography and Contributor Address File (Box 102-103)
  - Subseries III.3: Committee to Rescue Italian Art (CRIA), 1966-1968
    CRIA is a committee formed in response to the flood of 1966 in Florence, Italy. Subseries 3 contains: committee correspondence, photographs of the flood damage, academic articles on the damage done to works of art and manuscripts, and reports on committee work. Included are related books and articles on the flood.
    - General
      - 1966 (Box 104)
      - 1967 (Box 104)
      - 1967-1969 (Box 104)
    - Archivio di Stato di Firenze, 1966 (Box 104)
    - Articles, 1966-1967 (Box 104)
    - Articles, 1967-1968 (Box 104)
    - Booklets, 1966 (Box 104)
    - Photographs, 1966 (Box 104)
    - Reports and Related Material, 1966-1967 (Box 104)
    - Reports and Related Material, 1967-1968 (Box 104)
    - Scuola Città Pestalozzi Pamphlets--Numbers 1 through 6, 1967 (Box 104)
    - Scuola Città Pestalozzi Pamphlets--Numbers 7 through 10, 1967 (Box 104)
  - Subseries III.4: Journal of the History of Ideas, 1941-1987
    Subseries 4 includes committee correspondence, minutes and reports. Note that general folders include a mix of these three.
    - General, 1941-1946 (Box 105)
    - General, 1947-1955, 1977 (Box 105)
    - Correspondence
      - 1979-1982 (Box 105)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 105)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 105)
      - 1985 (Box 105)
      - 1992-1993 (Box 105)
    - Minutes and Reports
      - 1950-1968 (Box 105)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 105)
      - 1972-1977 (Box 105)
      - 1978-1987 (Box 105)
  - Subseries III.5: Professional Contacts
    This series is comprised of notecards listing Kristeller's colleagues from around the world along with their addresses, affiliations, and research interests.
    - Colleagues (Box 106-107)
    - Colleagues and Academic Institutions (Box 108)
    - Offices (Box 109)
    - Deceased and Institutions (Box 110)
    - Institutions (Box 111)
- Series IV: Columbia University, 1939-1989
  This subseries includes papers and records related to Paul Oskar Kristeller's long career at Columbia University, including material related to his teaching and activities as well as administrative and other University activities.
  - Subseries IV.1: Subject Files, 1939-1968
    The Subject Files subseries includes files related to Kristeller's activites at the University, including syllabi, a report on the University libraries Renaissance holdings, and information related to the Italian Department.
    - Course Syllabi, 1940s (Box 112)
    - Italian Department, 1952-1961 (Box 112)
    - Policy Matter and Research 1958-1967 (Box 112)
    - Report to Columbia University Library on Renaissance Holdings 1939-1941 (Box 112)
    - Columbia University Research Leave 1968 (Box 112)
    - Columbia University Student Riots 1968 (4 Folders) (Box 112)
  - Subseries IV.2: Correspondence, 1941-1989
    This subseries is comprised of Kristeller's correspondence regarding departmental and University matters. Also included in this subseries is correspondence related to theses and dissertations advised by Kristeller.
    - General
      - 1954-1960 (Box 112)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 112)
      - 1963 (Box 112)
      - 1964 (Box 112)
      - 1965 (Box 112)
      - 1966 (Box 112)
      - 1967 (Box 112)
      - 1968 (Box 112)
      - 1969 (Box 112)
      - 1970 (Box 112)
      - 1971 (Box 112)
      - 1972 (Box 112)
      - 1973 (Box 112)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 113)
      - 1976-1978 (Box 113)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 113)
    - Students Writing Theses Under P.O.K
      - 1941-1942 (Box 113)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 113)
      - 1945-1946 (Box 113)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 113)
      - 1947 (Box 113)
      - 1948 (2 Folders) (Box 113)
      - 1948-1950 (Box 113)
      - 1949 (Box 113)
  - Subseries IV.3: University Seminars 1945-1976
    This subseries includes records related to Kristeller's participation in the Columbia University Seminar on the Renaissance.
    - General, 1968 (Box 113)
    - Renaissance as Topic
      - 1945 (Box 113)
      - 1946 (Box 113)
      - 1947 (Box 113)
      - 1948 (Box 113)
      - 1949 (Box 113)
      - 1950 (Box 113)
      - 1951 (Box 113)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 113)
      - 1953-1955 (Box 113)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 113)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 113)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 113)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 113)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 113)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 113)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 113)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 113)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 113)
    - Columbia University Medieval Seminar, 1956-1976 (Box 113)
  - Subseries IV.4: Course Notes, 1940-1978
    This subseries includes lecture notes and course notes from courses taught by Kristeller over the course of his tenure at the University. These notes are arranged alphabetically by course title; with courses that Kristeller regularly taught the file may include notes from several years, showing how the course changed over time.
    - Aristotle, 1959-1960 Winter (Box 114)
    - Comparative Literature (Barnard), 1943 February (Box 114)
    - History of the Renaissance (Yeshiva College), 1944-1945 (Box 114)
    - Humanism and Philosophy in the Renaissance (Folger Institute), 1973 (Box 114)
    - Humanities, 1942-1943 (Box 114)
    - The Intellectual Current of the Renaissance (City College), 1974-1975 Spring (Box 114)
    - Introduction to Philosophy (City College), 1941 Summer (Box 114)
    - Introduction to Philosophy (Brooklyn College), 1946 Summer (Box 114)
    - Italian Literature of the Fifteenth Century, 1941-1942 (Box 114)
    - Italian Literature of the Fifteenth Century, 1946-1947 (Box 114)
    - Kant's Critique of Pure Reason, 1971 Spring (Box 114)
    - Leibnity Seminar at Columbia University, undated (Box 114)
    - Petrarca e L'Umanesimo (Barnard), 1943 October (Box 114)
    - Modern Philosophy Part I (City College), 1941 Summer (Box 114)
    - Philosophical Literature of the Renaissance, 1942-1943 (Box 114)
    - Philosophical Literature of the Renaissance, 1974-1975 (Box 114)
    - Philosophy I: Introductory Philosophy (City College), 1947 Summer (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 163: The History of Philosophy, 1955-1956 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 207: Seminar on Kant's Critique of Pure Reason, 1947-1948 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 247, 1953-1954 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 249: Seminar on Plato with [], 1955-1956 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 251: Philosophy, Origin and [], 1957-1958 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 207: Seminar on Kant's Critique of Pure Reason, 1947-1948 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 247, 1953-1954 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 249: Seminar on Plato with [], 1955-1956 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 251: Philosophy, Origin and [], 1957-1958 Winter (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 264: Post-Aristotelian Greek Philosophy, 1953 Spring (Box 114)
    - Philosophy 246: Seminar on Plotinus, 1947 Spring (Box 114)
    - Philosophy of Humanism and the Renaissance in Italy, undated (Box 114)
    - Philosophy of the Renaissance in Italy, 1940 Summer (Box 114)
    - Plato Seminar, undated (Box 114)
    - Plotinus, undated (Box 114)
    - Research Methods, 1940-1965 (Box 114)
    - Research Techniques (Folger Insitute), 1977-1978 (Box 114)
    - Seminar on Descartes, 1966 Spring (Box 114)
    - Seminar on Ficino and Pico (UCLA), 1979 January 22-February 28 (Box 114)
    - Seminar on Hegel, 1960 Spring (Box 115)
    - Seminar on Leibniz, 1951-1953 Winter, 1957 Spring (Box 115)
    - Seminar on Leibniz (City College), 1974 Fall (Box 115)
    - Seminar on Leibniz, 1975 (Box 115)
    - Seminar on Plato, 1969-1970 Winter (Box 115)
    - Seminar on Recent Continental Philosophy, 1952-1953 Winter (Box 115)
    - Study of Latin Palaeography, 1967, 1975 Spring (Box 115)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1974-1976 (Box 115)
- Series V: Writings, 1926-1995
  The writings series has been arranged in three subseries: Manuscripts, Lectures and Speeches, and Articles and Essays. Kristeller often had several drafts of his texts with extended annotation and revisions. Many of these drafts have accompanying research notes, notecards, and correspondence with librarians, colleagues, and publishers. This series spans Kristeller's entire career and contains writings in English, German, Italian, and French.
  - Subseries V.1: Manuscripts-- Books and Major Works, 1926-1992
    This subseries is comprised of manuscripts and drafts of Kristeller's major works and monographs. Correspondence related to the research, editing, publication, and distribution of volumes may be included, as may research notes compiled by Kristeller.
    - Bibliography, (4 Folders) (Box 116)
    - Correspondence regarding Manuscripts, 1948-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 116)
    - Der Begriff der Seele im System Plotins, 1927-1930 (Box 116)
      (dissertation)
    - Cicero Thesis (Box 116)
    - The Classics and Renaissance Thought, 1953-1955 (Box 116)
    - Dall' umanismo all'illuminismo, 1950-1967 (Box 116)
    - Early Philosophical Papers and Notes, 1920s (Box 116)
    - Eight Philosophers of the Italian Renaissance, 1961-1965, (4 Folders) (Box 116)
      (includes editorial correspondence and related documents)
    - Filosofia Greci dell'eta Ellenistica a Lezioni Comparettane, (2 Folders) (Box 116)
    - Greek Philosophers of the Hellenistic Age, 1992 (Box 116)
    - Initia Humanistica Latina (foreword), 1984 (Box 116)
    - Marsilio Ficino and His Work After Five Hundred Years-- Correspondence, 1969-1987 (Box 116)
    - The Philosophy of Marsilio Ficino
      - Project Proposal, 1932 (Box 117)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1958, 1974-1983, (2 Folders) (Box 117)
      - German Draft I--Part I, 1940s (Box 117)
      - German Draft I--Part I, 1940s (Box 117)
      - German Draft I--Part 2, 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 117)
      - German Draft II, 1940s (Box 117)
      - Italian Edition, 1984-1988 (Box 117)
      - Indices, 1940s (Box 117)
      - Project Description, 1932 (Box 117)
      - Research Materials, 1959-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 117)
    - Renaissance Concepts of Man, 1965-1972 (Box 117)
    - Renaissance Essays from the Journal of the History of Ideas, 1967 (Box 117)
    - The Renaissance Philosophy of Man, 1943-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 117)
    - The Renaissance Philosophy of Man, Excerpt, 1940s (Box 118)
    - Renaissance Thought and the Arts--Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 118)
    - Renaissance Thought and Its Sources
      - Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 118)
      - Draft, 1970s, (3 Folders) (Box 118)
    - Rhetoric and Philosophy, 1975-1978 (Box 118)
    - Rhetoric and Philosophy--German Edition, 1979-1981 (Box 118)
    - La Scuola Medica di Salerno…, 1957-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 118)
    - Le Thomisme, 1961-1966, (7 Folders) (Box 118)
  - Subseries V.2: Articles and Essays, 1926-1995
    This subseries contains articles and essays written by Kristeller over the course of his career. While most of these are academic pieces published in scholarly journals or volumes of edited essays, the subseries also includes some unpublished seminar papers from Kristeller's time as a student and a few less formal biographical pieces and interviews.
    - "L'Academie Platonicienne de Florence," 1958 (Box 119)
    - "The Alleged Murder of Simon of Trent (1475) and its Literary Repurcussions: A Bibliographical Study," 1967-1994, (7 Folders) (Box 119)
    - "Ancient Philosophy at Salerno in the Twelfth Century," 1958-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 119)
    - "Argumentum un Cratylum de Rectum Nominum Ratione," 1984 (Box 119)
    - "Un 'Ars Dictaminis' di Giovanni del Virgilio," 1958-1961 (Box 119)
    - "Aufgaben und Probleme der Handschriftenforschung," 1962 (Box 119)
    - Authority of the Doctors-- Preface (Box 119)
    - "Autobiography," 1989 (Box 119)
    - "Bartolomaeus, Musandinus, and Maurus of Salerno and Other Early Commentators of the 'Articella,' Within a Tentative List of Texts and Manuscripts," 1976 (Box 119)
    - "Between the Italian Renaissance and the French Enlightenment: Gabriel Naudé as an Editor," 1975-1979 (Box 119)
    - "Byzantine and Florentine Platonism," 1963-1968, (2 Folders) (Box 119)
    - Chapters in Renaissance Civilization-- "Renaissance Europe- The Moral Thought of Humanism," 1958-1959 (Box 119)
    - Cicero, 1930 February (Box 119)
      (Seminar Paper)
    - Cicero Pro Murena, 1929 (Box 119)
    - The Concept of "Demon" in Plutarch, 1929 (Box 119)
    - "Contemplation in Plotinus and Marsilio Ficino," 1981 (Box 119)
    - "La Cultura Umanistica a Roma nel Quattrocentro,"1981-1983 (Box 119)
    - "The Cultural heritage of Humanism: An Overview" (Box 119)
    - "Current Problems of the University and of Humanistic Scholarship," 1985-1989 (Box 119)
    - "The Current State of Ficino Studies," 1973 (Box 119)
    - "La Diffusione Europa del Platonismo Fiorentino," 1968 (Box 119)
    - "Un Documento Ignoto per la Biographia di Poggio Bracciolini," 1981 (Box 119)
    - "Un Documento Sconosciuto Sulla Giostra do Giulianuo de' Medici," 1939 (Box 119)
    - "Domenico Sforazzini e la sua Biographia di Marsilio Ficino," 1979-1986 (Box 119)
    - "The Editing of Fifteenth Century Tests: Tasks and Problems," 1983-1984 (Box 119)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica Entries, 1956-1957 (Box 119)
    - Encyclopedia of Comparative Iconography Entries, 1998 (Box 119)
    - Encyclopedia of Philosophy Entries, 1961-1965 (Box 119)
    - "Erasmus from an Italian Perspective," 1969 (Box 119)
    - "Erinnerungen an Karl und Gertrude Jaspers," 1994 (Box 119)
    - "The European Diffusion of Italian Humanism," 1962, (2 Folders) (Box 119)
    - The European Significance of Florentine Platonism (Box 120)
    - Ficino's Platonism and the Court of Urbino-- Preface (Box 120)
    - "The First Printed Edition of Plato's Works and the Date of Its Publication (1484)," 1965-1978 (Box 120)
    - "Florentine Platonism and Its Relations with Humanism and Scholasticism," 1939 (Box 120)
    - "De Formarum Sive Idearum Apud Ciceronem Notione" (Box 120)
    - "Francesco da Diacceto and Florentine Platonism in the Sixteenth Century," 1946 (Box 120)
    - "From the Italian Renaissance to the French Enlightenment: Gabriel Naudé as an Editor," 1973-1976 (Box 120)
    - "Der Gelehrte und Sein Publikum im Späten Mittelalterund in der Renaissance," 1960 (Box 120)
    - Gemistos Plethon's De Fato translated by Johannes Sophicanos," 1960-1970 (Box 120)
    - "Giovanni Pico della Mirandola and His Sources," 1963-1965, (3 Folders) (Box 120)
    - "Giovanni Pico della Mirandola and His Latin Poems," 1974-1976 (Box 120)
    - "Giovanni Senza Paura," 1994 (Box 120)
    - "The Greek Term Orexis," 1930 January (Box 120)
    - "Guglielmo Postel Lettore di Marsilio Ficino," 1982-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 120)
    - History, The Last Things Before the Last-- Forward, 1968-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 120)
    - "History of Philosophy and History of Ideas," 1962-1964 (Box 120)
    - A History of Western Philosophy: Renaissance Philosophy-- Forward, 1990-1991 (Box 120)
    - Humanism and Christianity-- Forward, 1967-1968 (Box 120)
    - "Humanism and Moral Philosophy," 1987-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 120)
    - "Humanism and Scholasticism in the Italian Renaissance," 1944-1945 (Box 120)
    - "Humanist Learning in the Italian Renaissance,"1959 (Box 120)
    - "The Impact of Early Italian Humanism in Thought and Learning," 1968-1969 (Box 120)
    - "L'influsso del primo umanesimo italiano sul pensiero e sulle scienze," 1968-1969 (Box 120)
    - Institute for Advanced Study Article, 1953-1954 (Box 120)
    - "An Interview with Paul Oskar Kristeller," 1988 (Box 120)
    - "Interview with Kristeller," 1995 (Box 120)
    - "Iter Kristellerianum: The European Journay (1905-1939)," 1995 (Box 120)
    - "Jewish Contributions to Italian Renaissance Culture," 1983-1984 (Box 120)
    - "John H. Randall, Jr. and Renaissance Philosophy," 1963-1967 (Box 120)
    - "John H. Randall, Jr.," 1981 (Box 120)
    - "Kurze Mitteilung uber Handscriftliche Funde" (Box 120)
    - Labalme Index, 1980 (Box 120)
    - "The Lachman Method: Merits and Limitations," 1980-1984 (Box 121)
    - "Latein und Vulgärsprache in Italien des 14 und 15 Jahrhunderts," 1983-1984 (Box 121)
    - "A Latin Translation of Gemistos Plethon's De Fato by Johannes Sophianos Dedicated to Nicholas of Cusa," 1970 (Box 121)
    - Latin and Vernacular in Fourteenth and Fifteenth Century Italy," 1983-1984 (Box 121)
    - "The Latin Poems of Giovanno Pico della Mirandole," 1964-1975 (Box 121)
    - "Lauri Quirini," 1968-1972, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "Learned Women of Early Modern Italy,"1977-1980 (Box 121)
    - "The Legacy of Renaissance Humanism" (Box 121)
    - "Una Lettera Inedita di Erasmo a Hutten Conservata a Firenze," 1980-1986 (Box 121)
    - "Liberal Education and Western Humanism," 1976, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "A Little Known Letter of Erasmus and the Date of His Encounter with Reuchlin" (Box 121)
    - "Ludovico Lazzarelli e Giovanni da Correggio, due Ermentici dea Quattrocento, e il Manoscrito II.D.I.4 della Biblioteca Comunale Degli Ardenti di Viterbo," 1960, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - Lorenzi de'Medici Book-- Preface, 1992-1994 (Box 121)
    - "Marsilio Ficino as a Beginning Student of Plato," 1966 (Box 121)
    - "Marsilio Ficino Letterato e Glosse a liu Attribuite nel Codice Caetani di Dante," 1978-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "Marsilio Ficino and the Roman Curia," 1984-1985 (Box 121)
    - "Marsilio Ficino as a Beginning Student of Plato," 1962-1965 (Box 121)
    - "Matteo de' Libri, Bolognese Notary of the Thirteenth Century and His Artes Dictaminis," 1951 (Box 121)
    - "Medieval and Renaissance Studies: Reflections of a Scholar," 1975-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "Methods of Research in Renaissance Manuscripts," 1974-1975 (Box 121)
    - "The Modern System of the Arts: A Study in the History of Aesthetics," 1950-1951 (Box 121)
    - "Moritz Steinschneider as a Student," 1958 (Box 121)